Bakke, E. Wight Papers 5522
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
E. Wight Bakke Papers
1903-1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Bakke, E. Wight
5522
55 cubic feet
55 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
Correspondence, subject files, note cards, lecture notes, and publications of economist E. Wight Bakke.
3338505
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
RS, January 18, 2000
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
E. Wight Bakke was born in Onawa, Iowa, to Harriet Frances (Wight) and Oscar Christian Bakke, a shoe merchant in Onawa. Bakke attended Northwestern University where he received a BA in Philosophy in 1926. He continued in the Yale Divinity School from 1926 to 1929 and during that time was also a pastor of the Park Methodist Episcopal Church. His graduate study in social sciences was also conducted at Yale University, and from 1931-1932 he was the Sterling Fellow at Yale, receiving his Ph.D. in 1932. In 1964 he received an honorary LL. D. from Northwestern University.
Bakke taught sociology at Yale from 1932-1934, and was an assistant professor of economics from 1934-1938. He served the Institute of Human Relations as Director of Unemployment Studies from 1934-1939, and was promoted to Professor of Economics in 1938 and appointed the Sterling Professor of Economics in 1940. Bakke was the Director of Graduate Studies in Economics at Yale from 1940-1950. From 1944 until the late 1950's he directed Yale's Labor and Management Center. The Center was devised with a nine-member policy committee made up of three representatives of Yale, three from labor, and three from management to develop a balanced approach and avoid an "ivory tower" view of labor relations.
Bakke was often called upon to advise governmental commissions and scholarly organizations on labor and management issues. He was Fulbright professor in Denmark in 1953, the principal consulting social economist for the Social Security Board from 1936-1939, and a consultant to the Department of Labor, Navy Department. He directed the National Bureau of Economic Research, and was the Chairman of the Appeals Committee of the National War Labor Board. He was a member of several Presidential Emergency Boards and the National Manpower Policy Task Force.
E. Wight Bakke died on November 23, 1971.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5960: E. Wight Bakke Additional Papers
Industrial relations -- Study and teaching -- United States; Industrial management -- Study and teaching -- United States; Bakke, E. Wight. (Edward Wight), 1903-1971; Yale University--Faculty.; Yale University Labor and Management Center
3338505
- A - Al, 1938-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Am -, 1942-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Association for Social Security, 1942-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- American Association for Social Security, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- American Association for Social Security, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- American Association for Social Security, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Am, 1946-1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- American Labor Conference on International Affairs, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- American Management Association to American Telephone and Telegraph Company, 1946-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- An -, 1952-1966 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Argyris, Chris, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Ar - Ay, 1945-1966 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Ba, 1941-1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bakke (relatives), 1950-1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Ba, 1941-1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bartos, Otomar, 1952-1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Bc, 1946-1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Black, Robert (The White Motor Co.), 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Bl - Bo, 1945-1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Br - Bu, 1936-1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Ca, 1945-1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Ce - Ch, 1945-1971 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Ch, 1945-1962 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Ch - Co, 1941-1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Co -, 1943-1966 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Confidential, A - L (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Confidential, M - Y, 1942-1966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Correspondence, Co, 1939-1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Copyright Office (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Cornell University, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Cornell University, 1940-1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Co, 1948-1968 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Cr - Cu, 1952-1968 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- "Crank Letters", 1946 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Da, 1941-1967 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Da, 1948-1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Da, 1935-1967 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- De - Di, 1945-1967 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Do, 1937-1945 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Do, 1958-1966 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Du, 1947-1968 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- E, 1940-1968 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Fa - Fi, 1940-1971 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Fi - Fl, 1937-1968 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Ford Foundation (Study of Employment Service in U.S.), 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Ford Foundation, 1951-1961 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Ford Motor Company, 1947-1952 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Foreign Operations Administration (European Productivity Agency), 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Foreign Operations Administration (EPA), 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Foreign Operations Administration Norway Project, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Fo, 1945-1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Foundation for Research on Human Behavior, 1957-1964 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Foundation for Research on Human Behavior, 1955-1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Fr - Fulbright Grant (Denmark), 1946-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Fu, 1936-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Ga - Gl, 1945-1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Golden, Clint, 1945-1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Go - Gr, 1941-1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Gr - Gu, 1943-1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Ha, 1940-1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Harvard College, 1940-1969 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Harvard College, 1935-1937 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Ha - Haverford College, 1958-1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Ha - He, 1936-1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- He - Hi, 1946-1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Hiton, John (England), 1932-1939 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Ho - Hu, 1940-1968 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Ib - In, 1945-1968 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Industrial Relations Research Association, 1957-1967 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Industrial Relations Research Association, 1957-1951 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Industrial Relations Research Association, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- In - Institute of Human Relations (see Bakke publications), 1938-1967 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- In - Iv, 1946-1970 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Ja - Jangard, Rolf, 1955-1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Japan Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Jo - Ju, 1945-1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Ka - Ke, 1945-1966 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Keller - Ke, 1937-1969 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Kerr, Clark, 1941-1968 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Ke - Ku, 1946-1965 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Labor and Management Center, Advisory Council and General, 1945-1952 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Labor and Management Center - Gifts, 1945-1953 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Labor and Management Center, Personal and Financial, 1937-1953 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Labor and Management Center, Policy Committee Members (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Labor and Management Center, Union Campaign Acknowledgement, 1945-1949 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Labor and Management Center, Union Gifts, 1944-1950 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Labor Education Service, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Labor Management to "Laboratories", 1940-1966 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- La - Le, 1941-1967 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Li - Lu, 1941-1968 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Lucius and Eva Eastman Fund, 1946-1951 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Lu - Ly, 1959-1967 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Ma, 1933-1962 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Ma, 1946-1970 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Maurice and Laura Falk Foundation, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Ma - Mc, 1942-1969 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Me, 1941-1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Mi - Mo, 1934-1967 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Mu, 1934-1967 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- My and Miscellaneous, 1949-1971 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- National Association of Manufacturers, 1960-1966 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Na - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1940-1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Na -, 1948-1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- National Planning Association, 1946-1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- National Policy Committee - Na, 1946-1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- National War Labor Board, 1944-1945 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- National War Labor Board, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Ne, 1940-1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Ni - No, 1943-1970 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Norway, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Norway Distribution Correspondence, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Norwegian ("Hands Across the Sea"), 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Norwegian, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Norwegian, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Norway - Nu, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Ob - Oh, 1946-1969 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Ol - Ox, 1948-1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Pa - Pe, 1947-1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Pensions for Nonprofessional Employees, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Pe, 1939-1963 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Ph - Pi, 1939-1969 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Pl - Pr, 1945-1971 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Princeton University, 1941-1967 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Pu - Publishers' Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Publishers' Correspondence, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Publishers' Correspondence, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Publishers' Correspondence, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Publishers' Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Publishers' Correspondence, 1956-1926 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Publishers' Correspondence, 1939-1949 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Publishers' Correspondence, 1932-1938 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Quinnipiac College (Jr. College of Commerce), 1959-1970 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Quinnipiac College (Jr. College of Commerce), 1946-1956 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Ra - Recommendations, 1945-1970 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Re - Rehn-O.E.C.D., 1961-1970 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Religious Society of Friends (Friends Association), 1939 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Religious Society of Friends (American Friends Service Committee), 1940 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Religious Society of Friends (American Friends Service Committee) - Treasury, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Religious Society of Friends (American Friends Service Committee) - Treasurer, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Religious Society of Friends (Connecticut Valley Friends), 1943-1945 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Religious Society of Friends (New Haven Monthly Meeting), 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Religious Society of Friends (New Haven Meeting), 1949 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Religious Society of Friends (New Haven Monthly Meeting), 1950 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Religious Society of Friends (Friends Service Committee - Workshops), 1951 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Religious Society of Friends, 1952-1969 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Re - Reynolds (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Rh - Riccardi (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Ri - Robbins (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Ro (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Rockefeller Foundation - Ro (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Rotival, Maurice - Ru (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Rudge (Fred) Associates, Inc., 1957-1961 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Rudge (Fred) Associates, Inc., 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Rudge (Fred) Associates, Inc., 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Ru (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Sa - Scandinavian Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Sc - Se (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Seymore, Charles (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Si - Sh (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Sk - Sm (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Social Science Research Council (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Social Security Board (Box 4, Folder 17)
- So - Socony-Vacuum Oil Company (Box 4, Folder 18)
- So - Sp (Box 4, Folder 19)
- St - Sy (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Ta - Tr (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Twentieth Century Fund (Box 4, Folder 22)
- UAW - Unemployment (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Unions, Management and the Public (Box 4, Folder 24)
- United Rubber to United States (Box 4, Folder 25)
- United States Department of Labor (Box 4, Folder 26)
- United States G... to University College of West Indies (Box 4, Folder 27)
- University of Akron to University of Colorado (Box 4, Folder 28)
- University of Connecticut to University of Kent (Box 4, Folder 29)
- University of Maryland to University of Michigan (Box 4, Folder 30)
- University of Minnesota to University of Rhode Island (Box 4, Folder 31)
- University of San Francisco to University of Wisconsin (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Upjohn Institute to Uyeno, Ichiro (Box 4, Folder 33)
- V - Wa (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Wa (Box 4, Folder 35)
- We - Wh (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Wi (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Williamson (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Willkie (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Wi (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Wo (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Wo - Ya (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Young Men's Christian Association to Young Women's Christian Association (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Yale, 1932-1944 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Yale, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  Scope and Contents
  May-July
- Yale, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  July-October
- Yale, 1946-1962 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Yale, 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Yale, Union Movement, Local 35, AFL-CIO, Yale University Employees (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Academic Freedom (Box 5, Folder 1)
- An Active Manpower Policy and Economic Fluctuations (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Active Manpower Policy, Industrial Relations Center, University of Minnesota (Bakke - Speaker) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Adaptive Human Behavior (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Adaptive Human Behavior ("notes for revision") (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Adaptive Human Behavior (diagrams used) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Adaptive Human Behavior (conferences between Holm, Argyris and Bakke) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Adaptive Human Behavior (a progress report from Chris Argyris) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Adaptive Human Behavior (miscellaneous notes) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- An Address to the Alumni, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  August 2nd
- The American Character and The American Charter (Box 5, Folder 11)
- 1) An Analysis of Labor Movements, 2) An Appraisal of the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics Cost of Living... 3) Approach to the Study of Social Stratification (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Balancing Incentive and Security (Box 5, Folder 13)
- 1) The Basic Issue in Labor and Management Relations, 2) The Basic Need for Social Insurance, 3) The Basic Principles of Human Relations (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Basic Realities in a System of Unemployment Benefits (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Basic Research in Human Relations (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Bedriftens Informasjonsproblem (Box 5, Folder 17)
- The Beveridge Plan and America (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Bonds of Organization (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Bonds of Organization (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Bonds of Organization, Tests of Efficiency (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Bonds of Organization, The Local Development... (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Bonds of Organization, Research Material (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Bonds of Organization, Research Material (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Bonds of Organization, Research Material (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Bonds of Organization, Charts (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Book Reviews (Box 5, Folder 27)
- British Experience with Unemployment (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Campus Challenge, Original Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 29)
- Campus Challenge, Original Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 30)
- Campus Challenge, Original Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Campus Challenge, Original Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Campus Challenge, Original Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 33)
- Campus Challenge, Original Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 34)
- Campus Challenge, Original Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Campus Challenge, Original Manuscript (Box 5, Folder 36)
- Campus Challenge, Outline and Bibliography Notes (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Campus Challenge, Another Copy (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Campus Challenge, Another Copy (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Campus Challenge, Another Copy (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Campus Challenge, Another Copy (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Campus Challenge, Another Copy (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Campus Challenge, India (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Campus Challenge, India (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Campus Challenge, India (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Campus Challenge, India (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Campus Challenge, India (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Campus Challenge, Egypt (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Campus Challenge, Egypt (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Campus Challenge, Egypt (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Campus Challenge, Research (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Campus Challenge, Research Bibliographies (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Campus Challenge, Book and Personal Contacts (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Campus Challenge, South American and Mexican Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Campus Challenge, Research Materials (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Campus Challenge, Research Materials (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Campus Challenge, Research Materials (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Campus Challenge, Research Materials (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Campus Challenge, Research Materials (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Campus Challenge, "Galleys" Bibliography (Box 6a, Folder 1)
- Campus Challenge, I. Preface, II. Appendix, III. Wiggen Memos (Box 6a, Folder 2)
- Campus Challenge, Section 5 (Box 6a, Folder 3)
- Campus Challenge, Duplicate (Box 6a, Folder 4)
- Campus Challenge, Second Page-Proof (Box 6a, Folder 5)
- Campus Challenge (Box 6a, Folder 6)
- Causes of Trade Unionism (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Certain Factors Reducing the Effectiveness of the Technical Assistance Program (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Characteristic Features and Functions of the Union (Box 7, Folder 3)
- City of New Haven (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Collective Bargaining in the Public Sector (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Communications: Sharing Information with Employees (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Concept of Social Organization (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Concept of Social Organization, another copy (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Concept of Social Organization (was published as Chap. 2 of a book entitled: Modern Organization Theory by Mason Haire) (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Concept of Social Organization, Research Material (Box 7, Folder 10)
- The Constitution (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Coordination of Manpower Services, Some Important Premises (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Copenhagen Lectures, Part I (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Copenhagen Lectures, Part II (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Cultural Factors in Industrial Relations (Box 7, Folder 15)
- The Debate on Socialized Medicine (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Democracy (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Democracy and Voluntary Groups (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Denmark Speeches, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Dimensions of Federal Manpower Policy (Box 7, Folder 20)
- 1) E.C.A. Group for Forestry Assoc., 2) Educational Objectives (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Eastern Water Company (Bakke - Speaker) (Box 7, Folder 22)
- 1) Employment Service in a Full Employment, 2) Ethnocentrism (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Employment Service, NY Department of Labor (Bakke - Speaker) (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Employment Service, The Key Agency in a Positive Manpower and Employment Program (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Employment Training, Industrial Relations Center, University of Minnesota (Bakke - Speaker) (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Evaluation of Langstroth Employee Diagnostic Survey (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Evaluation of Marxism (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Executive Leadership and Management, U.S. Bureau of Employment Security (Bakke - Speaker) (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Executive Leadership and Management, U.S. Bureau of Employment Security (Bakke - Speaker) (Box 7, Folder 30)
- 1) Experience of Japanese Students, 2) Explanation of My Research (Box 7, Folder 31)
- Extended Unemployment Compensation Benefits in the Post Armament Readjustment (Box 7, Folder 32)
- Facts Versus Theories in Great Britain (Box 7, Folder 33)
- The Fifth Winter of Unemployment Relief, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- The Fortune Survey: Fortune Magazine (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Framework for the Analysis of Industrial Relations: Two Views (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Framework for the Study of Human Relations (Box 7, Folder 37)
- From Tactics to Strategy in Industrial Relations (Box 7, Folder 38)
- From Tactics to Strategy in Industrial Relations (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Frontiers of Human Relations, Parts I and II (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Frontiers of Human Relations, Parts I and II (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Frontiers of Industrial Relations Research (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Function of a Trade Union in a Democracy (Box 7, Folder 43)
- The Fusion Process (Box 7, Folder 44)
- The Fusion Process, Research Materials (Box 7, Folder 45)
- The Fusion Process, Material for Continued Study (Box 7, Folder 46)
- 1) German Journalists, 2) The Government and Reemployment, 3) Governor's Committee on Public Employee Relations (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Graduate Education for Women at Yale (Box 7, Folder 48)
- Grunnleggende Forutsetninger for Human Relations Innenfor en Bedrift (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Grunnleggende Forutsetninger med Hensyn til Menneskelige og Organisasjonsmessige Factor (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Hazards in the Association of Employment and Unemployment Insurance Services (Box 7, Folder 51)
- Headline Edition (Box 7, Folder 52)
- High Talent Manpower Policy, Parts I and II (Box 7, Folder 53)
- High Talent Manpower Policy, Parts I and II (Box 7, Folder 54)
- Horizons of Human Relations (Box 7, Folder 55)
- How are Personnel Administrators Doing (Box 7, Folder 56)
- How Practical is Basic Research, Parts I and II (Box 8, Folder 1)
- How Practical is Basic Research, Parts I and II (Box 8, Folder 2)
- How to Promote Labor Peace (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Human Factors in the Management Organization (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Human Relations, In Norwegian (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Human Relations Audit of Structure, Operations and Effectiveness of Economic Organizations (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Human Resources Function, Parts I and II (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Human Resources Function, Parts I and II (Box 8, Folder 8)
- The Identity of Labor Organizations (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Immortality (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Impact of Human Relations on Production (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Importance of Human Relations (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Individual and Organizational Purposes (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Industrial Relations, First National Methodist Conference (Bakke - Speaker) (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Industrial Relations Research (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Institute for Industrial Effectiveness (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Institute of Human Relations (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Issues in Higher Education, Dean John P. Miller's Seminar (Bakke - Speaker) (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Japan and America (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Junior College of Commerce, Commencement (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Klein Institute (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Labor, Management and the Public Interest, Parts I and II (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Labor, Management and the Public Interest, Parts I and II (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Labor Management Relations Under Free Enterprise (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Labor Organization, First Part of the Draft (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Labor Organization, Chapter 5 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Labor Organization, Notes and Another Copy of Chapter 5 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Labor Organization, Progress Report, Synopsis, etc. (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Labor Organization, Notes and Drafts (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Labor Standards at Yale University (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Management's Human Relations Function and Charts (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Management's Responsibility for Worker's Security (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Manpower Policy During a Recession, Part I (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Manpower Policy During a Recession, Part II (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Mass Demonstrations (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Men, Management and Organization (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Mission of Manpower Policy (Box 8, Folder 37)
- Money Isn't Everything (Box 8, Folder 38)
- Mutual Survival (Box 8, Folder 39)
- Mutual Survival, The Issue (Box 8, Folder 40)
- Mutual Survival After Fourteen Years (speeches) (Box 8, Folder 41)
- Mutual Survival, Reviews (Box 8, Folder 42)
- Mutual Survival, Labor and Management Center Pub. (Box 8, Folder 43)
- Nature and Purpose (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Nature of the Public Interest in Labor and Management Relations (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Need for Scientific Study of Human Relations in Industry (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Obstacles to Labor-Management Peace (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Occupational Revolution, Chapters 1 - 5 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Occupational Revolution, Chapters 6 - 7 (Box 9, Folder 6)